Francisco Alfredo Uribe Sánchez

Fullstack Developer & Project Leader

https://alfredouribe.com/ https://github.com/alfredouribe/

alfredo.uribe.sanchez@gmail.com

+52 44 32 37 39 43

♀ Calle Sol, Edificio E, Dep 101, Cosmos, 58050, Morelia, Mich.



Summary Statement

Computer Science Professional with 10 years of experience successfully delivering End to End web applications to small, medium and large companies of several business models. Experienced with HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, JavaScript, AJAX, MVC, Bootstrap, Git, MySQL and PHP. I am looking forward to digitally transforming organizations with state of the art technologies.

Experience

PHP Lead Developer – **Terra**July 2020 – Current

Responsibilities

- Developed from scratch an RRHH enterprise platform focused in the administration of employees, assignment of assets and cars management. The platform has 18 modules where several business processes were defined and automated. Designed, developed, tested and implemented the 18 modules with PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap, jQuery, AJAX, Web Services, JSON, AWS s3 services and several jQuery plugins. Enabled 100% platform availability with no production bugs.
- Re-engineered and built an ERP web application with more than 100 modules for the processes of:
 get items to inventory with buying process including imports models, inventory calculators,
 warranty process, manage installations, technical support, implements of error's validations. Led
 and coached 4 interns for the development of a project management set of modules within the
 platform.
- Managed projects life cycle from end to end, gathered requirements with product owners, provided software estimations and implemented agile principles on a daily basis.

PHP Lead Developer – **Solfine** July 2016 – July 2020

Responsibilities

- My first role is to fix all bugs that exist with the purpose of improving the operation; I also made new implementations to facilitate new tasks, and scripts that fix all the misinformation that was saved with the wrong calculations in this payroll system.
- Planified, developed, led, and implemented a Real Estate web application with broker's communication.
- Implemented, analyzed and verified the law process for the correct hiring and managing information for employees and payments process linked to a bank service.
- Managed projects life cycle from end to end, gathered requirements with product owners, provided software estimations and implemented agile principles on a daily basis.

Python Developer – **Divox**June 2018 – October 2018

Responsibilities:

- Architected and launched a predictive web analytics platform to obtain insights on political preferences for a political campaign. Built both the backend and frontend modules with python, MySQL, Bootstrap, AJAX, Django. Acted as developer and project manager of the initiative.
- Learned Ionic Framework from scratch in order to build a payments mobile application for CFE, OAPAS, TELCEL, TELMEX. Successfully delivered the application in a 1 month period of time. The App had 5 modules built with python services, angular, ionic, firebase for notifications. Deployed the app services in a private infrastructure.

PHP Developer – **Televisa** October 2015 – July 2016

Responsibilities:

 Built new modules for main websites of Unicable, Golden TV, Ritmoson, Telehit with JSP in AEM CQ5 technologies. Collaborated with cross functional teams to define website design, backend architecture, testing strategy and project planification.

Projects as Independent Consultor

- https://visagroup.mx/ (CMS)
- http://uribebrickpavingco.com/ (Website)
- https://bonanit.com.mx/ (Website)
- http://rapidomaravatio.com/ (App Android, Website)
- http://ismsantacecilia.com/ (Website)
- http://radioterapia.org.mx/ (Website)
- https://ilmaestrouniforms.com/ (ecommerce)

- http://transportesexpresso.com/ (Website, ERP)
- http://www.herraline.com.mx/ (Online semistore)
- CUCITEC (Magazine online)*
- ENDOPERIO (ERP Dental clinic)*
- Moreliato (Magazine online)*
- AlMedical y MedicalPharm*
- UNEDEPROM (Magazine online)*
- Exavall (Website)*

Education

Computer Engineering Universidad Michoacana de San Nicolás de Hidalgo June, 2015

Bachelor in Computer Administration Universidad Sor Juana Inés de la Cruz December, 2016

Skills

PHP	HTML5	CSS3
Bootstrap	jQuery	JavaScript
Xampp	Linux	Git
Office	MySQL	JSON
XML	VMWare	SmartGIT
PHPMyAdmin	Python	Django
AEM6	SCRUM	Trello
SOAP	API REST	SQL Server
Angular	Laravel	Ionic

^{*}Some repositories were deleted from my account because they are private